Md Mahin Arafat

Lippincott St, Toronto, ON M5T 2R5

+1 (647) 997-7035 - mahinarafatmeem@gmail.com

mdmahinarafat.netlify.app | github.com/mahin12 | linkedin.com/in/mahin-arafat

Summary

Currently a post-graduate student of Electrical and Computer Engineering at Ontario Tech University with 2 years of experience in web development with a strong understanding of software architecture, agile and scrum methodologies, JIRA, and Git. Motivated to work on digital transformation and innovation, software development life-cycle, cloud platform and looking for opportunities to grow.

Education

Masters of Engineering CGPA 3.73/4.33	2022 - 2023		
University of Malaya Bachelor of CS in Compu CGPA 3.24/4.0	2017 - 2021		
	Tools	s & Skills	
 Web development Python, Django Java HTML, CSS, SCSS Documentation Git, Bitbucket JIRA 	 Heroku SQL, MySQL React.JS API Software Modelling IntelliJ Bootstrap 	 PHP SUMO Eclipse jQuery Docker JavaScript Agile Methodology 	 PyCharm, PhpStorm Photoshop, Lightroom, FCPX Software Architecture and Modelling MS Office Source Control
	Relevant	Experience	
Sirius App Messenger			

Sirius App Messenger

Ontonia Took Haironsitus

Freelance Software Engineer

June 2022 - Present

- Helping with making a robust code base for upcoming projects
- Using React.JS and APIs on development
- Integrating the codebase between frontend and the backend
- Learning client management and understanding responsibilities to shape the project

Strativ BD Limited

Junior Software Engineer

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

- Worked on different web development projects
- Learned to work on client-based projects, and attended and dealt with multiple clients
- Utilized knowledge in SQL, Python, Django, and JavaScript
- Changed the entire theme and added functionalities for the internal ERP system

Saleduck Asia

Web Application Developer Intern

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

- Worked with the development and maintenance of various websites of Saleduck
- Worked in SASS, PHP, Laravel framework, HTML and CSS
- Used professional product management tools and developer tools like Bitbucket, Slack, Git, Docker etc.
- Learned the basics of backend development and database such as MySQL
- Followed and learned deeply and used the model, view and controller and used the components to maintain the system architecture

Strativ BD Limited

Software Engineering Summer Intern

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Participated in changing website designs according to the clients' requirements
- Learned how to make codes more effective and efficient using bootstrap tools

Projects

	· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	
•	Data Visualization (<i>Tableau, Python</i>)	
•	Personal Portfolio Website (Gatsby, JavaScript)	
• '	Vehicle Movement Detection based on Device Movement (Sumo, Python)	
•	Fire Hazard Detection System (Fortran, Python)	
•	Car Rental and Vehicle Breakdown assistant (Python, Django)	
•	Personal Finance System Website (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, React.js)	
	Minimum Spanning Tree Finder (<i>Python</i>)	
	Smart English Tutor (Software Requirement Engineering)	
	Trello Landing Page (HTML, CSS, jQuery)	
	Traffic Light System (Machine Language)	
	Number Guessing Game A.I. (JAVA)	
	Bank Management System (JAVA)	
Personal Blog (WordPress)		2016